Guide to the Isidor Schneider Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Isidor Schneider Papers,
1925-1975
Schneider, Isidor, b. 1896.
ca. 5,000 items (20 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079312
Biographical Note
American poet and novelist.
Scope and Content
Manuscripts and correspondence of Schneider, including numerous manuscripts of short stories and poems, many of which are unpublished, and several full-length manuscripts of unpublished critical works. The collection also contains an extensive file of typescript reports on books for The Book Find Club, clippings of reviews written by Schneider and about his books, photographs and drawings of Schneider, and a file of correspondence relating to his writings. The literary correspondence includes letters from many of the important novelists, poets, and literary critics from the 1920s to the 1950s. They include Conrad Aiken, Sherwood Anderson, Kenneth Burke, Malcolm Cowley, Theodore Dreiser, Waldo Frank, Lillian Hellman, Robert Hillyer, Alfred Kreymborg, Thomas Mann, Arthur Miller, Marianne Moore, Lewis Mumford, Laura Riding, Muriel Rukeyser, Karl Shapiro, Stephen Spender, Mark Van Doren, and Yvor Winters.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 12 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Inscribed Books
Series III: Notebook and Manuscripts
Series IV: Manuscript and Reviews
Series V: Books Relating to Schneider
Series VI: Book Find Club Book Reports
Series VII: Manuscripts by I. Schneider
Series VIII: Books with Contributions by I. Schneider
Series IX: Collected Books and Journals
Series X: Articles and Reviews
Series XI: Book Reports for George Braziller
Series XII: Book Reports for George Braziller and Grove Press
Subjects
Book Find Club.; Aiken, Conrad, 1889-1973.; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941.; Burke, Kenneth, 1897-1993.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Frank, Waldo David, 1889-1967.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Hillyer, Robert, 1895-1961.; Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-1966.; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955.; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005.; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Riding, Laura, 1901-1991.; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980.; Shapiro, Karl Jay, 1913-2000.; Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Winters, Yvor, 1900-1968.; Critics.; American literature--20th century.; American poetry--20th century.; Book clubs (Discussion groups); Women authors.; Authors.; Drawings.; Photoprints.; Poets, American.; Authors, American.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 3-22. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1966 M-66 Schneider, Isidor Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidor), New York, 22 January 1923, (4 p. a.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidor), New York, 14 February 1923, (5 p. a.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidor), [New York], [1923], (8 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidor), [New York], [1923], (4 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidor), On board S.S. Adriatic, 12 March 1923, (1 p. a.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Conrad To: Isidor Schneider, Boston, Mass., 4 November 1925, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [ca.1927], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood To: Isidor Schneider, Marion, Va., 25 September 1928, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Eleanor (Mrs. Sherwood) To: Isidor Schneider, New York, 2 February 1947, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Ayscough, Florence Wheelock (1878-1942) To: Isidor Schneider, St. Andrews, N.B., 28 September [n.y.], (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Ayscough, Florence Wheelock (1878-1942) To: [Malcom] Cowley, St. Andrews, N.B., 28 September [n.y.], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Ayscough, Florence Wheelock (1878-1942) To: Isidore Schneider, St. Andrews, N.B., 28 September [n.y.], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Beals, Julia To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], 13 February 1967, (1 p. t.l.s (with a.l.s. from Schneider on bottom)) (Box 1)
    [Includes related material]
  - Benet, William Rose To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
    [Written on the bottom of a letter from Schneider to Benet dated 1 March 1944]
  - Benet, William Rose To: Isidore Schneider, New York, [n.d.], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Benet, William Rose To: Isidore Schneider, New York, [n.d.], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Richmond To: [Horace B.] Liveright, Newport, R.I., 8 June 1926, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Benet, William Rose To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 Christmas card, signed with note) (Box 1)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil To: Isidore Schneider, [Hollywood, Calif.], [March 1944], (1 p. t.l.s) (Box 1)
    [Written on the reverse of a letter from Isidore Schneider]
  - Benet, William Rose To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [n.d.], (2 p.. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: Isidore Schneider, Barto, Pa., 7 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: Isidore Schneider, Barto, Pa., 27 October 1944, (12 t.l.s (with note added in his hand)) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: Isidore Schneider, Barto, Pa., 7 March 1946, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], 21 May 1961, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Le Rouret, France, 23 June 1961, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: [Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider], [Le Rouret, France], 23 June 1961, (4 p. t.ms. (carbon copy; inscribed to Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider) ) (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen To: Helen Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), [n.p.], 4 July 1975, (1 p. t.l.s. (includes two m.s. poems ca. 1945 by M. Brand)) (Box 1)
  - Bragin, Moe To: Isidore Schneider, Brooklyn, 23 August 1975, (2 p. a.l.s. (includes related material on International Literature letterhead)) (Box 1)
  - Brewster, Dorothy To: [Isidore Schneider], [New York], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l. (written on bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944) ) (Box 1)
  - Brown, William Slater To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. t.l. ) (Box 1)
  - Buckmaster, Henrietta To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. March 1944], (1 p. t.l. (typed on bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Burgum, Edwin Berry To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. March 1944], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 15 December 1931, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Isidore Schneider, Andover, N.J., 3 October 1932, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 23 January 1933, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 17 March 1933, (2 p. t.l.s (includes NY Herald Tribune clipping of Schneider's review)) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 12 January 1936, (2 p. t.l.s (with Schneider's letter to Burke dated 14 January, 1936)) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Edwin Berry Burgum, New York, 20 February 1936, (1 p. t.l.s (with typed letter from Burgum to Burke)) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To: Isidore Schneider, Melbourne Beach, Fla., 2 April 1941, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Burt, Maxwell Struthers To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (2 p. a.l.s (written on the bottom and verso of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley To: Isidore Schneider, New York, [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. t.l. (written on the bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Carnevali, Emanuel To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. t.l. ) (Box 1)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), New York, 15 March 1930, (1 p. a.l.s (draft of Mrs. Schneider's reply enclosed)) (Box 1)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), New York, 15 March 1930, (1 p. a.l.s (draft of Mrs. Schneider's reply enclosed)) (Box 1)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 20 December 1944, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 13 march 1946, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cirino, Linda To: Isidore Schneider, Leonia, New Jersey, 29 January 1974, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cirino, Linda To: Isidore Schneider, Leonia, New Jersey, 4 March 1974, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Chodorov, Edward To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s (written on bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Corey, Ruth To: Isidore Schneider, Sonoma, California, 18 August 1975, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [Plus related material]
  - Cowley, Malcom To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcom To: Isidore Schneider, New York, [n.d.], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcom To: Isidore Schneider, Gaylordsville, Conn., 5 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcom To: Isidore Schneider, Gaylordsville, Conn., 30 August 1946, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcom To: Isidore Schneider, Millstone, Conn., [n.d.], (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Peggy Baird (Mrs. Malcom) To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Gaylordsville, Conn., [n.d.], (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Crighton, Kyle To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 3 March 1944, (21 t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Albert To: Isidore Schneider, Brooklyn, 6 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Babette To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 5 June 1928, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Babette To: Isidore Schneider, Greenwich, Conn., 31 August 1928, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Babette To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), New York, 9 March ]1930], (2 p. a.l.s, t.ms.s. 1 p. Poem, to Emily) (Box 1)
  - Dos Passos, John To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [Ocober 1936], (1 p. a.l.s (with Schneider's draft reply, a.l.s., 1 p. and related note)) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [1 December 1926], (1 p. a.l.s (with a typescript of a review by T.P. O'Conner of An American Tragedy) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], 20 April 1927, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [ca. 12 May 1927], (2 p. a.l.s (written on bottom and verso of a letter from Schneider to Dreiser dated 12 May 1927)) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 12 May 1927, (1 p. t.l.s (with Dreiser's holograph notations and corrections)) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [22 May 1927], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 1 April 1931, (1 p. t.l.s (signed by Dreiser's secretary, Evelyn Light)) (Box 1)
  - Faragoh, Francis Edwards To: Isidore Schneider, Los Angeles, Calif., 26 December 1935, (4 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Frank, Waldo David To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 13 October 1925, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Fried, Alexander To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), New York, 28 August 1928, (3 p. a.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Fried, Alexander To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), [New York], 30 September 1923, (3 p. a.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Fried, Alexander To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), [New York], [22 October 1923], (2 p. a.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Fried, Alexander To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), [New York], [31 October 1923], (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Friede, Donald To: Isidore Scneider, New York, 26 December 1929, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Gessner, Robert To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s (written on bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Gessner, Robert To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s (written on bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Gresham, William To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944 ], (1 p. a.l.s (written on bottom of letter from Schneider dated 1 March 1944)) (Box 1)
  - Griffiths, Ginette and David To: Helen and Isidore Schneider, Victoria, B.C., 24 August 1973, (1 p. t.l.s. (includes photocopy of a Russian language pamphlet)) (Box 1)
  - Griffiths, Ginette and David To: Isidore Schneider, Victoria, B.C., 28 may 1973, (2 p. t.l.s. (includes related material)) (Box 1)
  - Griffiths, Ginette and David To: Helen and Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], 30 November 1974, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Griffiths, Ginette and David To: Helen and Isidore Schneider, Victoria, B.C., 15 December 1974, (1 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Griffiths, Ginette and David To: Helen and Isidore Schneider, Victoria, B.C., 30 August 1975, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Hanline, Maurice To: Helen and Isidore Schneider, New York, 8 August 1928, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Hazlitt, Henry To: Isidore Schneider, Wilton, Connecticut, 23 October 1971, (1 p. t.l.s. (includes related material)) (Box 1)
  - Harris Roy To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d. ], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Harris Roy To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d. ], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hansen, Harry To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 24 February 1931, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hartmann, Sadakichi To: Isidore Schneider, Beaumont, Calif. 26 June [n.y.], (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hazlitt, Henry To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), New York, 16 March 1929, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hazlitt, Henry To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, New York, 26 June 1928, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hazlitt, Henry To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, New York, 6 August 1928, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hazlitt, Henry To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Sanary-sur-Mer, France, 5 June 1929, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hazlitt, Henry To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Sanary-sur-Mer, France, 22 June 1931, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hellman, Lillian To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), [n.p.], [n.d.] [1928?], (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hellman, Lillian To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Pleasantville, N.Y., 1 October 1941, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Schruns (Voralberg) Austria, 23 March [1926], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Schruns (Voralberg) Austria, 23 March [1926], (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Juan les Pins, France, 29 June [1926], (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, [Paris], France, [ca. October 1926], (3 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Gstaad, Switzerland, 18-19-20 January [1927], (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Gstaad, Switzerland, 14 February 1927, (1 p. t.l.s (with a.n.s. in pencil on verso)) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Rimini, Italy, [22 March 1927], (1 p. t.p. (addressed in the author's hand)) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, [Paris?], France, 18 May [1927], (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Paris, France, 18 May 1927, (2 p. a.l.s. (xerox)) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Mr. & Mrs. Isisdore Schneider, [New Jersey], [n.d.], (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Isidore Schneider, Yaddo [New York], [ca. October 1935], (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, [New Jersey], 3 April [n.y.], (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Key West, Florida, 10 April 1930, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Isidore Schneider, Key West, Florida, 18 February 1931, (5 p. t.l.s. (a carbon copy of Isidore Schneider's reply and two clippings are enclosed)) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Isidore Schneider, Key West, Florida, 19 February 1931, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Isidore Schneider, Key West, Florida, 7 March [1931], (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herbst, Josephine To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidore), Yaddo, New York, 30 June 1932, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Herman, Peter F. To: Isidore Schneider, Rochester, New York, 10 May 1973, (1 p. t.l.s. (with a.l. response by Schneider on bottom of letter)) (Box 1)
  - Hersy, John To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1941], (1 p. t.l.s. (written in response to Schneider's letter looking for humerous America writing)) (Box 1)
  - Hicks, Granville To: Isidore Schneider, Grafton, New York, 21 August 1934, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Hill, Frank To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 7 June 1930, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Hillyer, Robert To: Isidore Schneider, Pomfret, Connecticut, 8 September 1928, (1 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Hillyer, Robert To: Isidore Schneider, Cambridge, Mass., 12 November 1928, (1 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Hyman, Stanley To: Isidore Schneider, Winchester, N.H., 10 June 1942, (5 p. t.l.s. (with carbon copy of letter from Isidore Schneider)) (Box 1)
  - Hyman, Stanley To: Isidore Schneider, Bennington, Vt., 10 Novemebr 1953, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Jolas, Eugene To: Isidore Schneider, Paris, France, 10 August 1928, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Jolas, Eugene To: Isidore Schneider, Paris, France, 6 February 1927, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Jolas, Eugene To: Isidore Schneider, Paris, France, 8 January 1927, (1 p. t.l.s (per secretary)) (Box 1)
  - Josephson, Matthew To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, [New York], 17 March 1930, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kahn, ALbert To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (writen on a letter sent by Schneider)) (Box 1)
  - Kahn, Albert To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (writen on a letter sent by Schneider)) (Box 1)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 11 June 1930, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To: Isidore Schneider, Cambridge, Mass., 14 January 1930, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To: Isidore Schneider, Cambridge, Mass., 22 October 1929, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To: Isidore Schneider, Cambridge, Mass., 23 December 1929, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To: Isidore Schneider, Cambridge, Mass., 3 January 1930, (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kober, Arthur and Lillian (Hellman) To: Emily Schneider, New York, 20 March [ca. 1930], (1 p. telegram) (Box 1)
  - Kober, Arthur To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Paris, France, Summer 1928, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Komroff, Manuel To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 10 August 1928, (3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Komroff, Manuel To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 15 September 1928, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kramer, Aaron To: Helen Schneider, Oakdale, New York, 23 September 1974, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 29 March 1929, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 4 March 1946, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kuntiz, Stanley To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca.1928], (1 p. a.n.s. (written on clipping biography of I. Schneider)) (Box 1)
  - Liveright, Horace To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 5 April 1929, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Liveright, Horace To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 19 October 1928, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Liveright, Horace To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 11 October 1928, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Lattimore, Owen To: Isidore Schneider, Peking, China, 8 May 1931, (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - McFee, William To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (in response to Schneider's request for pieces of American humour)) (Box 2)
  - McKenny, Ruth To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [ca. October 1935], (3 p. t.l.) (Box 2)
  - McKenny, Ruth To: Isidore Schneider, Tucson, Arizona, [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. t.l.) (Box 2)
  - Mailer, Norman To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [ca. 1969], (1 p. t.l. (Autograph on mimeo political flyer)) (Box 2)
  - Maltz, Albert To: Isidore Schneider, Los Angeles, California, 3 April 1946, (2 p. t.l.s) (Box 2)
  - Mancisidor, Jose To: Isidore Schneider, Mexico City, Mexico, 18 September 1946, (1 p. t.l.s (in Spanish)) (Box 2)
  - Mangione, Jerre To: Isidore Schneider, Philidelphia, Pa., 7 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mann, Thomas To: Isidore Schneider, Pacific Palisades, California, 14 April 1948, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mead, Margaret To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 30 October 1930, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mead, Margaret To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 18 November 1930, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mead, Margaret To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 4 March 1941, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Millay, Kathleen To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 26 September 1928, (2 p. t.l.s (enclosed t.ms. of Millay book review ) [New York, ca. Sept. 1928]) (Box 2)
  - Miller, Arthur To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1945], (1 p. a.l.s (enclosed t.ms. of Miller's brother's poem, "Another Serves") ) (Box 2)
  - Miller, Arthur To: Isidore Schneider, Reno, Nevada, 13 October 1960, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Miller, Arthur To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], 26 January 1960, (1 p. t.l.s (with envelope)) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 16 October 1924, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 22 October 1924, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 9 December 1924, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 8 February 1925, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 23 June 1926, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 20 August 1926, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 15 October 1928, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 5 November 1928, (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, 9 August 1929, (2 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 17 July 1928, (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 25 June 1928, (1 p. a.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 11 January 1929, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 14 January 1929, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 11 February 1929, (1 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Amenia, New York, 5 July 1928, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, Amenia, New York, 31 August 1928, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Isidore Schneider, Amenia, New York, 2 September 1929, (2 p. t.l.s ) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Mr & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, [Vienna, Austria], 2 September 1929, (p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Mr & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, [Vienna, Austria], 8 June 1932, (p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Isidore Schneider, Amenia, New York, 20 July 1933, (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Isidore Schneider, Amenia, New York, [193-], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 27 October 1939, (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Ormtz, Samuel To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 24 June 1927, (1 p. t.l.s. (signed by secretary)) (Box 2)
  - O'Sheel, Shaemas To: Isidore Schneider, Red Hook, New York, 5 December 1939, (5 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Palmer, Earle F. To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 6 September 1928, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 13 November 1939, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Piscator, Erwin To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], 15 March 1946, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Putnam, Phelps To: Isidore Schneider, Aiolo, Italy, 3 July 1934, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)